Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/tushar-gerg-1a98904a (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Java

Databases

Software Development

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)
Spanish (Limited Working)
Hindi (Professional Working)

Tushar Gerg

PM Consultant / Al Engineer

New Delhi, Delhi, India

Summary

As a Product Manager with a technical bent of mind, I love backing up my intuition with data that speaks reality. I love analyzing products, understanding customers, and creating/executing enhanced roadmaps for products that delight customers and result in a high ROI.

Throughout my career, I have worked on products in E-Commerce, Media, Banking, and have also founded a social mobile startup. Started out as a software engineer with a deep focus in AI, I have realized a strong passion for products that have shaped my PM career, and used my technical expertise to an advantage every step of the way.

Experience

Unicorn Technologies Consultant August 2016 - Present

step for cross-functional teams.

New Delhi Area, India

Pitched and delivered product enhancements to businesses

It's All About Home - IAAH (Furniture E-Retail, Noida, India)
Lead E-Commerce Product Strategy, Development, Marketing (iaah.com)

- Defined and executed strategy for acquiring, converting and retaining customers through market research, user behavior analysis, segmenting / understanding target
- groups.

 Set attainable targets such as product adoption, engagement, user conversion, retention and positioned performance metrics calculations at every
- Developed product roadmaps focusing on enhancing user experience through loyalty programs, efficient navigation and search, live chat, shop filters, quality product display.

- Ensured seamless mobile experience (80% traffic) through responsive design, A/B testing, cross-device testing, minimal design wireframes, intuitive maneuvering, usage analytics.
- Installed strategies for user profiling and retargeting to improve product and generate leads through website analytics, data-driven segmentation, google/facebook/instagram targeting.
- Managed development of fully functional E-Commerce platform with ERP using Agile.
- · Devised and executed online marketing strategy.

Impact Research and Measurement (Media Monitoring Company, New Delhi, India)

Enhanced offerings by the business by identifying and executing AI based opportunities

- Analyzed business and strategized product enhancements.
- Added product features leveraging Artificial Intelligence, producing a high ROI & competitive advantage.
- Automated calculation of key news metrics which allowed insight into a large volume of web/print media instantly.
- Delivered solution to group similar news through AI increasing insight extraction ability and highlighting highest performing stories.
- Identified process optimizations and delivered automation to batch-process historical news.
- Classified all incoming news through state of the art Machine Learning models in production.

Floot (Mobile Dating Startup)

Founder

August 2015 - August 2016 (1 year 1 month)

Greater New York City Area

Created mobile dating app for US market focused on delivering a real experience

- Functionality included location based matching in real-time, date scheduling, automatic date-spot selection, chat, reviews, innovative revenue models for businesses and users.
- Designed prototype ensuring optimal UX with minimal budgets to roll out Android/IOS MVP.
- Developed backend architecture, integrating 3rd party APIs, algorithms and data models.

- Created Marketing plan, Product Roadmap, Investment plan detailing market size/potential.
- Managed Mobile App Development, Created development milestones,
 Conducted Surveys
 and Competition Analysis, Pitched to Investors, Showcased and presented at
- Featured on iHeartRadio in New York, placed 3rd in 'Startupalooza' startup competition.

JPMorgan Chase Associate August 2014 - July 2015 (1 year) Greater New York City Area

conferences.

Analytics Lead in Cyber Intelligence and Fraud disruption

Designed Real Time Fraud Detection and Prevention Systems

Engineered Analytics Systems to detect electronic fraud trends, generate real-time alerts through Machine Learning algorithms using user electronic activity data. Specifically employed techniques such as anomaly detection, pattern matching, supervised classification of user sessions, geo-clustering, distributed data analysis using Hadoop infrastructure.

Developed web crawlers to fetch relevant intel and use it for negative pattern matching, for example cyber security forums and indictment lists matching with machine data for fraud indication, new accounts opening etc, all in the online banking domain.

Tech used included Python ('scikit learn', 'scrapy' libraries), Java, Matlab, SAS, splunk SDK.

Nationwide Insurance Software Engineer September 2013 - August 2014 (1 year) Columbus, Ohio Area

Enterprise Automation Software Development
Programming Languages used include Java, C#, Ruby.

Automated Business rules integration for Big Data, Algorithm development for Insight Learning, Data Validation, Test Automation, Risk Analysis.

Built Production environment monitors, data validation tools, QA task automaters, Business Rules Engine and more.

Analyzed Business Requirements to craft Project Specifications, Mock-ups and delivered in Agile Management Environment.

Florida Institute of Technology
Teaching Assistantship
September 2012 - May 2013 (9 months)
FIT, Melbourne Fl

Algorithms and Data Structures, Advanced Java

LexisNexis
Software Developer - Big Data Processing
June 2012 - September 2012 (4 months)
Boca Raton, Florida, USA

ETL with Ab Initio Software and Enterprise Control Language (ECL – HPCC proprietary language)

Work included creation of new data processing graphs, file analytics in UNIX, data transformation & validation, field cleaning, filtering, string manipulation.

HPCC Systems Big Data Analytics Platform (Open Sourced)

Sona Koyo Steering Systems Ltd R&D Intern July 2010 - September 2010 (3 months)

R&D Intern for Steer by Wire Technology (automatic steering systems)

Studied a company patented design which included two electric motors - my work involved eliminating one by strategically placing spring system to provide mechanical recoil.

Education

Florida Institute of Technology
Bachelor of Science (BS), Computer Science (2009 - 2013)

Florida Institute of Technology
Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Computer Science (2009 - 2013)